<Document>
  #GENERAL RULES
  These rules apply at all times, both in character and out of character, and are enforced universally.

  ##Language
  - Using non-standard unicode is forbidden, this extends to the use of emojis, symbols and all other forms such as text emojis like “:), :(, :D, xD” regardless if done through emotes, through announcements or as a label on an object.
  - Spamming chat with non-english characters, symbols or other gibberish is forbidden.
  - CMU is an English speaking server. Speaking full sentences in anything but english is not allowed. Single words or phrases in other languages are allowed so long as it compliments your RP (your character referring to their "padre", "amigo", etc is fine). 

  ##Do not Metagame
  - Don't use information gained from outside your character's knowledge to gain an advantage.
  - Using information you gain from outside your own character's view and hearing to your advantage is strictly forbidden. You remember all events up until you fall unconscious. If you take a ghost role or respawn, unless otherwise stated, you do not remember anything from your past life.
  - Do not post images/videos of or discuss on-going rounds until after the round has concluded.
  - Players may be in a voice chat with each other while playing the game, but must not share information that could be used to metagame.
  - Retrieving or completing objectives for a faction as a third party or unrelated party, without being informed of that faction’s objectives, is considered metagaming.

  ##Don't intentionally annoy/antagonize other players.
  - You are playing a multiplayer game with other people who also want to enjoy the game.
  - Do not intentionally make other players lives hell for your own amusement.
  - Do not spam emotes/sounds for no reason (this includes screaming, reload spam, etc).
  - Intentionally making yourself a major problem/annoyance/disruption for other players in your faction at large is forbidden.
  - There is leeway for minor and moderate crimes that benefit your character, which has consequences for your character if caught.
</Document>