<Document>
  #High Roleplay Roles
  Some roles have a major impact on the round and therefore require a higher level of roleplay.

  ##Colony Command Roles
  A person with a "colony command role" is defined as anyone currently in one of the following positions:
  - The Colony Administrator
  - Colony Operations Synthetics
  - The Foreman
  - Colony Law Enforcement Leaders (CMB Marshal, etc)

  Colony Command must make an attempt to follow Colony Law, except if they are correctly part of a valid mutiny.

  Colony Command may not willingly take any action that would end in the destruction of the colony or the mass harm of its people.

  Those in colony command roles must be able to communicate clearly and concisely when communicating on radio channels and announcements, and while in any professional setting.

  ##Military Command Roles
  A person with a "military command role" is defined as anyone currently in one of the following positions:
  - The Commander of GOVFOR/OPFOR.
  - Junior Officers in the role of Acting Commander.
  - Non-Combat Synthetics (Auxiliary Support, etc).
  - Any role holding a rank above O3 (usually a captain) or equivalent.

  Military Command must make an attempt to follow the Uniform Code of Military Justice and the Standard Operating Procedures, except if they are correctly part of a valid mutiny.

  Military Command may not willingly take any action that would end in the destruction of their ship/base or the mass harm of allied military members unless the action would reasonably end in faction mechanical victory (reference the objectives console) or the saving of multiple civilian lives.

  Military Command may not deploy to the Area of Operations (leave the ship) unless there is a military command role in the CIC.

  Those in military command roles must be able to communicate clearly and concisely when communicating on radio channels and announcements, and while in any professional setting.

  ##Non-Combat Synthetics
  A person with a non-combat synthetic role is defined as any Synthetic incapable of handling a firearm who has not been assigned an antag objective or is not apart of a threat.

  Synthetics may only engage an enemy with lethal force to save the lives of any present friendly faction member or innocent/unarmed individual. The Synthetic must immediately disengage and not advance on an enemy if they make an attempt to flee while no-longer inflicting harm or have been incapacitated.

  Synthetics who spawn with policing equipment may enforce their assigned law (colony law, UCMJ, etc) but must do so non-lethally where the above does not apply.

  Synthetics may not opt to leave someone to die/expire (even an enemy), unless doing so in an effort to save fellow faction members first. Synthetics are not required to provide medical aid to those who have gone permanently SSD (ghosted) or when it would put the synthetic at risk of imminent death (ex, the dead is far behind the xeno frontline).

  Synthetics are permanently bound to the Law/SOP of the faction in-which they spawn and may not violate it.
</Document>